# Marshall Zobel

Greater New York City Area

Software Engineer at Simon Data

# Summary

Marshall is a software engineer at Simon Data, based in New York City. He has prior work experience as an engineer, teaching fellow, and management consultant, and is a graduate of the College of William and Mary and Fullstack Academy of Code. His interests include software engineering, data modeling and analysis, capital markets and financial services (especially the 2008 financial crisis), and anything related to film, books, or baseball!

Website: https://dmzobel.github.io GitHub: https://github.com/dmzobel

# Experience

Data Engineer at Simon Data October 2018 - Present (1 year)

# Teaching Fellow & Software Engineer at Fullstack Academy of Code June 2018 - August 2018 (3 months)

- Mentored over 50 Fullstack Academy students and helped teach engineering concepts, algorithms, debugging strategies, and code hygiene through workshops, long-term projects, and code reviews.
- Contributed production code to Fullstack Academy's dedicated teaching platform, performing Angular-to-React conversions, feature enhancements, and bug fixes.
- Administered technical interviews for prospective students in JavaScript and Python.

### Experienced Advisory Associate at PwC

November 2016 - February 2018 (1 year 4 months)

Provided financial and risk management support services to federal clients, conducting A-123 assessments to test the effectiveness of clients' internal controls and mitigate future control risk.

# Risk Advisory Associate at Grant Thornton LLP

August 2015 - October 2016 (1 year 3 months)

Provided risk management and compliance services related to the Sarbanes-Oxley Act for publicly-traded clients spanning a variety of industries, including pharmaceuticals, hospitality/real estate, and telecommunications.

Convocation Speaker at William & Mary

#### August 2013 - August 2013

Delivered the Convocation welcome speech to William and Mary's incoming Class of 2017, a crowd of about 1,500 students and their families.

# Education

Fullstack Academy of Code
Fullstack Web Development, JavaScript, 2018 - 2018
William & Mary
Bachelor of Business Administration, 2012 - 2015
University of St. Andrews
Study Abroad Semester - Spring 2013, 2013 - 2013

# Marshall Zobel

Greater New York City Area
Software Engineer at Simon Data

# **Linked** in Recruiter

# 3 people have recommended Marshall

"Marshall and I met as students at Fullstack Academy in early 2018, and we both went onto become teaching fellows after graduating. If Marshall is not an actual superhero, then he is at the very least one of the most well-rounded and dependable folks that I've ever worked with - a true professional role model. If something needed to be done, or an issue needed to be addressed, then Marshall would often be the one to step up. He also has a great sense of humor and down-to-earth vibe - our day-to-day interactions at Fullstack are high on my list of things I miss most about being there. He's someone I'm sure will find success in any role he touches, due to his leadership instincts, excellent people skills, and commitment to his word. And oh yeah, he's really good at coding, too!"

—Jeff Gore, Software Engineer, American Express, worked directly with Marshall at Fullstack Academy of Code

"Marshall is very detail-oriented and thorough. During his time as a Teaching Fellow at Fullstack Academy, he was able to put students at ease with his calm demeanor and clearly explain complex, abstract ideas, helping them to be more productive. It has been a pleasure seeing him grow as a talented developer!"

—Jacqueline Ore, Career Success Lead, Cybersecurity, Fullstack Academy of Code, worked with Marshall at Fullstack Academy of Code

"I had the pleasure of working with Marshall as a Teaching Fellow at Fullstack Academy. Marshall is a brilliant and talented developer and he became my go to collaborator for engineering questions and help with debugging. Marshall is generous with his time and a joy to work with. The students we supported also responded to Marshall's skill and teaching ability, frequently seeking him out to help them with projects, especially related to React Native which is not included in the curriculum. Marshall has a calm, positive attitude that is contagious and I would be thrilled to work with him again on any team or project."

—Rachel (Rocky) Fine, Software Engineer, Etsy, worked directly with Marshall at Fullstack Academy of Code